Summary

- Python developer since 1998.
- Can deliver any web application from napkin design to Django POC in 72 hours.
- Full-stack capable.
- Welcome challenging problem.
- Have a high standard in work quality.
- SalesForce advocate.
- 4 Also available in: linkedin, PDF.

Skills

Software Development Python, C, ODOO/OpenERP, SQL, Salesforce APEX, Cordova, Google App Engine (GAE), Git, SVN, Bower, Yeoman, Jira

Web Application Django, Ansible, ReactJS, AngularJS, jQuery, Materialize, Bootstrap, Jinja2, Pelican

Data Visualization Graphviz, Cytoscape.js, netjsongraph.js, D3plus, Highcharts, Google chart, MetricsGraphics, chart.js, Plotly.js, dygraphs

QA Selenium, HP LoadRunner, SonarQube, Cucumber, Redmine, Bugzilla

System design pencil & paper, UML, PlantUML, Dia, Visio

System deployment Amazon EC2/RDS/S3, uWSGI, Nginx, Apache2, Builtbot, Fabric

System monitoring ELK stack, InfluxDB, Grafana, Cacti, Nagios

System administration Salesforce, Red Hat Satellite, Red Hat RHHI, Red Hat Ansible Tower, AWS

Documentation LaTex, Markdown, reveal.js, Confluence, Org mode, Word, Powerpoint, Excel, MS Project, Taskjugger

Experience

11/2016 - L present

Lenovo US, Advisory Engineer

- AuthoroftheLenovo Open Cloudreference architecture and Red Hat Hyperverged Infrastructure for Virtalization reference architecture. Published on 5/5/2019.
 - Tools: Pandoc, Markdown, BibTex, XeLaTex, GNU make, CSS
 - Sample writing:
 - Lenovo Open Cloud Reference Architecture: pretty draft in PDF, official version
 - 2. Red Hat Hyperconverged Infrastructure for Virtualization Reference Architecture: pretty draft in PDF, official version
- Lenovo Open Cloud product. Drove overall network design. Developed Python scrips and playbooks to automate RH Satellite deployment and configuration. Led development of playbooks to automate RHHI deployment on baremetal.
 - Tools: RedHat RHHI, RedHat Satellite, RedHat Ansible Tower, RHEL 7 server cloud image, KVM/virsh

- Sample writings:

- 1. Config Lenovo switches ENOS & CNOS
- 2. Config Lenovo server to RAID
- 3. RH Satellite
- Lenovo Open Cloud product. Forked Netbox by Digital Ocean. Retrofit its models and added functions to make it data center planning and orchestration tool. Extended Netbox architecture to include Redis for async task. Scripted switch and server scanning to draw topology of server-switch & switch-switch physical connections. Source code in github.
 - Tools: Django, Celery, Redis, Postgresql, Ansible, pexpect
 - Sample writings: Netbox design
- VX Installer product. Designed system architecture. Coded Django backend and RESTful API.
 - Tools: Django, Tastypie, Celery, Redis, Ansible, Canonical charms, Docker
 - PPT: Architecture of VX Installer
- Workload Solution Store project. Evaluated service orchestration technologies and developed Lenovo's core competence in automating baremetal provisioning.
 - Tools: Openstack, Ironic, Juju, MaaS, Canonical charms, Python, LXD, KVM, Virtualbox
 - Sample writings:
 - 1. MAAS lab
 - 2. Juju charm's reactive framework
 - 3. introduction of Openstack Ironic
 - 4. comparison analysis of Ironic vs. MAAS
 - 5. technologies used in baremetal provisioining

PY Consulting, Founder & Consultant 01/2015 -11/2016

- Wei Fashion Group project. Wei Fashion Group is an international fashion product trading company. Designed and built an inventory management and order tracking system in four weeks. Developed Android prototype in two weeks. Played a key role in setting up its Shenzhen subsidiary. Invited as feature speaker by "2016 Jiuzhou e-Commerce Convention" on Dec 8th, 2015, Shenzhen, China.
 - Tools: Django, Bootstrap, jQuery, Cordova, AngularJS, AWS, uWSGI, Nginx
 - **Demo**: view project Fashion for details
 - Source: github
- GKP project. Designed a web reference tool assisting Chinese high school graduate selecting domestic colleges. Featuring information about 3,383 colleges and universities, 1,663 majors, two million historical exam records and 50,000 lines per minute live chat stream.
 - Tools: Django, Bootstrap, Redis, Google map API, Baidu map API, Baidu Echarts, TOR API, Privoxy, AWS, uWSGI, Nginx
 - Demo: view project GKP for details
 - Source: github

- Stock analysis project. Developed an open-source web application that runs stock trading simulation with step-by-step transaction trace. User can test strategy and view comparisons with actual S&P500 daily data and China's S&P500 equivalent. Asynchronous design puts CPU intense computation to background processed by multithreading consumer.
 - Tools: Django, Bootstrap, Redis, Highcharts, AWS, uWSGI, Nginx
 - **Demo**: view project Stock for details
 - Source: github
- Linkage project. Linkage Ltd. is a Chinese start-up software company specializing ODOO module development. Built ODOO's continuous integration (CI) server. Customized ODOO inventory management system. Authored the company's "2016-17 Technology Roadmap".
 - Tools: Python, ODOO, Buildbot
 - Sample writings: Linkage 2016-17 Technology Roadmap (in Chinese)

11/2013 - Beijing Lean Strategy Consulting Group, Director 01/2015

- Responsible for a \$3-million fixed-bid software contract. Client is a Fortune-500 company. Project included designing and developing full-stack web and mobile applications which replaced three legacy systems.
 - Tools: Python, ODOO, Buildbot
 - Reports (in Chinese):
 - 1. 晋能集团数据中心建设分析 规模和成本
 - 2. 晋能集团云平台建设和使用咨询报告
- Design system architecture using SOA technologies. Managed evaluation of ESB, BPM and database components.
 - Tools: IBM Rational, MySQL, Java Spring Struts Hibernate, JBoss ESB, Mule ESB, Apache ServiceMix, Activiti BPM
 - Reports (in Chinese): 数据库技术和系统测试简介
- Supervised two vendor invitation-for-bids. Responsible for \$1.2-million RMB (\$200,000 USD) purchase.
- Managed QA team to automate regression tests. Coded two thousand test cases in TDD syntax, Python Unittest and Selenium webdriver. Built QA continuous integration infrastructure using Jenkins and SonarQube.
 - Tools: Python, Selenium webdriver, PhantomJS, Jenkins, SonarQube
- Enhanced company's standard operating procedure (SOP), including initiation of an online knowledge base, a project management system and a configuration management system.
 - Tools: Redmine, SVN
- Setup a local service team. Screened hundreds of resume and interviewed nearly one hundred candidates.

github.com/fengxia41103

fengxia41103@gmail.com

07/2010 - CrunchTime! Information Technology, Project Manager 11/2013

Tools: Salesforce APEX, Visualforce, Jira, MS Project, Taskjuggler

- Provided technical support to client on administrating our ERP product. Initiated statement-of-work(SOW) and followed it through development, user-acceptancetest(UAT) and deployment.
- Played a key role in pre-sales to Yum!China, Yum! s most profitable branch at the time. Analyzed over 600 pages of requirements covering operation of fourteen departments. Worked closely with CEO and Yum! s senior executives to outline deal structure. Participated in all key decisions regarding this deal.
- In charge of administrating Salesforce production instance, including setting up workflows, triggers, approval processes, a customer portal and a vendor portal.
- Customized Salesforce Customer Portal using APEX, Visualforce and jQuery. The portal won Bronze in the "2011 Steve Awards for Sales & Customer Service".
- Built the company's first mobile application prototype using Cordova, HTML5 and ¡Query Mobile.
 - Tools: Cordova, HTML5, jQuery mobile, Google map API, AT&T yellow page API
- Built user-acceptance-test(UAT) library using Python-Selenium, reducing one UAT cycle from 40-man-hour to less than 2 hours.
 - Tools: Python, Selenium webdriver, Django

04/2009 - China Everbright Bank, Business Manager 04/2010

Tools: Word, Powerpoint, Project

- Supervised two vendor invitation-for-bids. In charge of a \$2-million purchase of a software system. Managed system implementation, customization, training and administration.
- Setup Business Analysis team from ground up. Created report templates and analysis framework. Analysis results were the basis of two loans of substantial amount.
- Led team to create drafts of contracts, business policies, workflows and training materials.

04/2004 - Bit 9 Inc. (Carbon Black), Team Lead **05/2007**

Tools: NT kernel, Python, Graphviz, VC++, rootkits, VMWare

- Led a breakthrough in endpoint application control product, which played a key role in winning Bit9 a \$6-million B-round led by Kleiner Perkins.
- Member of Bit9's SaaS team. Built the world's largest Windows binary repository at the time featuring four billion data records. Wrote C++ parser for Windows binary PE formats.

07/1998 - Instron Corp., Senior Engineer

04/2004

Tools: RTOS, C, VB, PLC, Python

• Developed embedded controller of Instron's impact tester line (9250HV).

github.com/fengxia41103

fengxia41103@gmail.com

- Developed embedded controller of two million-dollar projects. Led system training.
- Initiated a new product line closed-loop Brinell hardness tester.
- Assisted in training the company's first Chinese R&D team.

Education

04/2007 - MBA, Boston University

09/2008

- Major: International Management Program
- **GPA: 3.75/4.0**
- Recipient of "High Honor and Dean's Achievement Scholarship"
- "Certificate of International Management Program"
- •• 2nd place in the "13th Annual Net Impact Case Competition"

09/1995 - Master of Science, Ohio University

05/1997

Major: Power System Automation

GPA: 3.15/4.0